We have one last chance.
To do what?
To rob the collection tonight.
Have you lost your mind?
Did you see what they have in there?
Wire fences, jammers, fighting bulls…
This isn't the Paris heist.
They shot Bruce
for setting foot on that estate.
It's a miracle he and Keila survived.
You're right. Paris is Paris.
And this is Spain's underbelly.
We must rise to the challenge.
Catch, Damián.
So, shooting our way in is your only plan?
You're wrong.
We'll go in through the door,
like we own the place.
Here are the magnetic keys
to gain access to the estate.
What do we do with that guy?
You and Roi are going to stay
and watch him.
Since he's our guest.
Pick the buckshot from his face
and disinfect his wounds
so he can go home tomorrow good as new.
I'm not a nurse, but I can drive
into the estate and haul ass right back.
Jesus, Berlin, I think I can be
a lot more useful there than here.
More than Bruce. No offense.
Cameron, this isn't
for professional reasons but personal.
I'm doing this for you.
For your romantic reconciliation.
Stay and watch this scoundrel.
You'll see how well it works out for you.
Hand on the trigger, adrenaline, fear…
That reinvigorates any couple.
Or do any of you want
to apply to be leader of the crew?
Hey, are you all right?
No, Bruce, I'm not.
Earlier, in this same vehicle,
I thought you had been killed.
Hey. In the end, nothing happened.
All thanks to you.
Racing in like Ayrton Senna.
Bruce, before we go back in there,
I need to tell you something.
I had doubts for a while.
I had a…
a moment of confusion with a guy.
I only saw him once. It wasn't planned.
It didn't mean anything.
What are you talking about, Keila?
Kissing, being turned on, banging?
- Yes.
- Yes to what, Keila?
It was sexual contact.
But just once. No repeats.
When that man took you at gunpoint, I…
I panicked. And I froze.
When I thought
that I might not see you again,
this overpowering force came over me.
I pictured myself doing the unthinkable,
running that man over.
I swear, if he had done something to you,
I'd have bashed his head in with a stone.
Bruce.
You are the force that moves me.
I know it hurts, but I had to tell you.
Well, now you have.
We are approaching the entrance.
We're going in. Be ready.
Thermal sensors
show no orange or red blobs.
No one in a 30-meter radius.
Turn off the lights.
The electric fence is six meters ahead.
No heat sources. We can go in.
The air vent is three kilometers
to the northeast.
Stick to this route, Damián.
I see infrared radiation.
- Where?
- Behind the bushes. On the left.
Roll down your window.
I can't see through the branches.
There are a few of them now.
We're being followed. Let's go.
Wait.
Bulls. Don't be hysterical.
Kill that flashlight.
You left marks on my face,
and no one messes with my face.
Shut up. Save your energy
for hunting wild boars.
Let her go, dammit!
Let her go, you bastard!
Roi! No!
- Let go of her, dammit!
- Shoot!
Fucking shoot!
Why didn't you shoot?
I can't shoot a guy for biting your hair.
He was gonna rip my face off, asshole!
Berlin asked us to keep him alive.
Know what Berlin would've done?
Pumped him full of lead.
You're all bark and no bite. A lapdog.
What I am is loyal.
Something you wouldn't understand.
What? Got nothing to say?
That's why you can't work with me.
You're ashamed.
You can't look me in the eye
after what you did.
I warned you.
- I told you who I am and what I can give.
- Did I put a gun to your head?
You did everything but.
You got on your knees,
begging me to give us a try. Remember?
You confused me. You messed with my head.
Do you know why you ignored
everything I said?
You're a fucking pushover.
What's so funny?
You.
How little you know about women.
It's easy to see she's the wild one.
You're the tame one. The pushover.
- Shut up.
- You can't handle her.
For a woman like her,
a dozen of you wouldn’t cut it.
Shut up, goddammit.
Two months in, they despise you.
Didn't you hear me?
I said shut the fuck up!
Oh, you think you’re tough now?
Why don't you try that on her?
You're a weakling.
Look who had the last word.
You just stood there looking stupid.
Do what you gotta do, dammit! Come on!
We're here.
Let's do it.
Looks like it's over 100 feet deep.
The duke didn't exactly roll out
the red carpet for us.
- Clear.
All clear. Come down.
Bruce, you okay?
Are you stuck?
Bruce, why'd you stop?
What kind of sexual contact?
Bruce, this isn't the time.
So, in the truck,
it was the time, but not now?
You decide when it's okay?
Keila, all okay?
Where did it happen? In our bed?
- No.
- Did you sleep together?
No, we didn't sleep.
Did you orgasm?
Bruce, please stop.
So you did.
Did you like it better?
Bruce, Keila.
Come down immediately.
That way.
We are 2,000 feet away from the cellar.
The alarm lasers could be anywhere.
- In the tunnel or in the cellar.
- How will we find out where they are?
We'll use a dense medium. Smoke machines.
Clear. Let's move.
Lie to yourself as much as you want.
You can believe
I forced you to be with me,
but you loved me, Cameron.
And I still love you.
Berlin is right.
Here we are in Spain's most gorgeous city,
wasting our time hating each other.
When I could fix all of this
with one kiss, right here and now.
Then we'd hold hands.
And get off this boat.
And head out and go wild in the city.
We'd lose ourselves
in Triana's oldest bars.
All full of noise and people.
We'd have to get close to hear each other.
You like when I talk into your ear.
You used to say it tickles you.
You, fearless as ever,
would break into a flamenco dance.
Everyone would be watching you, rapt.
Starting with me.
I'd try to clap along,
but with no flair at all
because I've got no rhythm.
Then we'd linger, kissing each other.
Motionless, in a sea of people.
We'd do all the silly tourist stuff
and feel like we were discovering it.
We'd go to the most expensive boutique
in town,
where aristocrats buy clothes,
and dress up like them for a while.
And damn, we'd look so good.
We'd get in a horse-drawn carriage
and go around Seville
for all the world to see.
Finally, we'd spend the night
at the most luxurious hotel in town.
And I say "spend,"
because we wouldn't sleep at all.
Cameron…
What?
Was what happened that night so bad…
that it ruins any chance for us?
It was you.
It's your fault, Roi.
It was you who pushed me over the edge.
That's why it all fell apart that night.
You always tried to change me.
To save me.
But all you've done
is screw me up even more.
We can't pretend it didn't happen.
Why?
This is all a big mistake.
I shouldn't have come to Seville.
Cameron.
- Tell Berlin I'm done. I can't be here.
- Cameron! For fuck's sake!
I won't calm down, dammit!
Last stop.
The dome we spotted with the drone.
Don't move.
Not another step.
It's like a laser cage.
The collection's in there.
It's odd. I'm not detecting cameras.
They don't need any with this setup.
These lasers
work like any photoelectric cell.
Trip the laser, and you activate an alarm
or something worse.
Something worse?
For an eccentric like our duke,
any twisted little trap.
Like the floor opening up
and dropping us into a pit.
Dead.
Alive. Dead.
Yeah, we get the idea.
But how will we get past
the best security system in the world?
His security system
was the best until a few years ago.
Keila, go on.
According to classified documents,
the duke installed the system in 2000,
but it's now a bit obsolete.
A weakness was found a few years ago.
I made a video to show you.
The laser has a two-degree tolerance
at the entry point.
Enough for us to fool the alarm.
How?
We'll swap their laser beam with our own.
Same frequency, power, and size.
Once we fit our laser
in that extra space in the receiver,
we cover the emitter and make an opening.
How will we know
the right power, frequency, and size?
The smoke will let us see
the beam's diameter.
We'll just have to analyze the frequency
with a spectrometer.
Two millimeters.
And once we have the laser
with the exact size,
how will we overlay it on the system
with a two-degree variation?
No human hand is that precise.
Exactly, no human hand.
We'll use neurosurgery robotic arms.
We'll be able to set the laser
in the exact point of the spectrum,
without even a 1-degree variance.
Berlin, scan the space.
We need to move the robotic arms
432.6 millimeters
to coincide with the lasers.
With an exact angle of 91.36 degrees.
Set the laser pointers.
Here we go.
I've seen faster robots.
C-3PO would run circles around this gizmo.
I need to make sure
the parameters are correct.
- This level of precision takes time.
- Fine. I'll shut up.
Look at this bastard's setup.
The wine barrels, the albero sand floors…
Nobody sets all this up
unless they're hiding something huge.
It's the moment of truth.
We'll block the real alarm lasers.
I think we fooled the system.
Your girlfriend's a pro.
There's our way in.
Shit.
Come on. Fuck.
The number you called is switched off
or unavailable.
Leave a message after the tone.
Damián, I hope you get this in time.
The guard escaped.
I was on deck.
He can't have left the boat.
I'll get far from land so he can't escape.
Damián, if that fucker
manages to warn the duke, you're dead.
You can go through
by lifting your leg carefully.
Your shoelace is untied!
Take your boots off.
Okay, coming.
I feel like a chump getting told
to take my shoes off at the airport.
I once made the mistake
of flying commercial.
They made me stick my feet
in tiny blue plastic bags
to get through security.
I've traveled by boat ever since.
And now, Keila, if you'll allow me…
Ready for the big moment?
The Storm on the Sea of Galilee,
by Rembrandt.
The real one.
Stolen from Boston's
Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum
23 years ago.
Poppy Flowers,
by Van Gogh.
This one was stolen twice
from the Cairo Museum.
View of Auvers-sur-Oise.
Cézanne.
Woman with a Fan, Amedeo Modigliani.
This was stolen from Paris's
Museum of Modern Art.
The Nativity,
by Caravaggio.
The most valuable stolen painting
in all of art history.
And he has them here, in his cellar.
As one keeps bottles of port.
What's with him? Is he having a breakdown?
- Big-time Stendhal episode.
- What?
Stendhal syndrome.
Euphoria causing palpitations,
happiness, and fascination
when contemplating beauty.
We'll admire it all tomorrow.
I don't want to stay here much longer.
We cut the canvases off
and leave the frames, right?
What are you doing, you fool?
You want to take them in the frames?
Of course not, Damián.
Because we're not taking them.
What do you mean?
These are not an empress's necklaces
or a cache of unmarked bills.
Before you are the greatest stolen works
in history.
The world's most mysterious
and coveted paintings.
But that contemptible,
egomaniacal narcissist
has them here, sequestered.
There are millions of paintings
around the world.
If people can't see these,
they will go see others.
Come, please.
Do you know how many times
I've visited the Uffizi Gallery
to bask in the presence
of The Birth of Venus?
Every time I am depressed
and lose faith in human nature.
And do you know
why I go there time and time again?
Because when I gaze upon that piece,
I regain my calm.
What is art, Bruce?
The highest vibration of the human soul.
Each one of these paintings
was created to reconcile
the human soul with the beauty
and pain of the world.
But this duke is so arrogant
that he had to set up this bordello here
with its stolen art,
its wine, its bed, and even its landline
to cheat his own inhibitors
and have his dinner
brought to his chamber.
It's repugnant.
So then what do we do?
Give me three minutes. I need to think.
Is this the right place to do that?
He could be watching us!
Don't worry. There aren't any cameras.
What if there's sonar or a detector?
And if he already knows we're here?
Look at the marks on my face
because I'm going to ask you a question.
Look at me!
Tell me.
Do you like dogs?
There are only two answers, yes or no.
Yes or no?
Yes.
Then bark.
Bark, dammit! Bark!
- Bark!
- Woof!
- More!
Good boy.
That's it. It's been three minutes.
Put that painting down right now.
What are you going to do?
Point a gun at me?
I won't.
You forced the gang
to pick your plan over mine,
because robbing deposit boxes was madness.
You convinced them and humiliated me.
Now in this laser cage,
you decide we're not stealing these?
We're robbing this place.
We sure as hell are.
That Monet is coming with me,
even if I can only hang it
in my office at school.
Hang on.
You're completely right.
But I just had an epiphany.
And I've seen things clearly.
These works of art, these pieces,
will be the key to the biggest
and most poetic heist in history.
And we'll do it together.
You and I.
I'm asking you, for everything
you hold sacred, trust me.
Keila, can you hide this landline's number
if I make a call?
Yes, of course I can.
Do it.
You told me to put on the clothes
laid out on the bed.
I've been waiting for 40 minutes.
I was on the porch,
seeing off our guests, love.
Right.
Come.
My toreador jacket fits you like a glove.
I hope this is not my birthday present.
Because… I'm not so sure I like it.
No.
This is just a little whim of mine.
Your present's here.
Piñatas?
Nothing like the eager excitement
of our childhood birthday parties.
I love children's games.
You can only break two piñatas.
Choose well, my love.
Hello?
Good evening, Duke. It's Berlin.
Forgive me for calling this late,
but I believe there's something important
that you and I should discuss.
At this hour? Can't it wait?
Let's say it can't.
I think it's best
if we get together tonight.
I'm with my team,
and I'd like you to meet them.
You see, I'm nearby, on your estate.
Inside your art gallery, to be precise.
My art gallery?
We'll be waiting here.
I'll go right away.
You're really leaving?
But I'm your wife.
Álvaro.
I think you're more
into your collection than into me.
I'll be right back, darling.
Don't take that off. You look beautiful.
Let me out, you bastard!
I put you in there with my lame doggie.
Her fate was sealed.
Let me out of here, you son of a bitch!
Give me that finger. Here.
Let go.
Don't move. That's it.
You've been good dogs.
I'm putting you out of your misery.
No!
No, please!
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy